# Himani Mewada

## **BUSINESS ANALYST**

**♀** Ahmedabad

**+91 9722407234** 

mewadahimani@gmail.com



#### OBJECTIVE

Adaptable and high-energy team player looking for a job as a Business Analyst position, coming with 4.10+ years of experience in the IT product industry. Ready to serve proficiency with documentations, wireframing, prototyping, flow charts, UML diagrams & Project Management.

#### EDUCATION

B. Tech in Computer Engineering- U. V. Patel College of Engineering - Kherva - 2013-17 - 8.1 CGPA

H.S.C from Shree Vardhman Vidyalaya- Mehsana, Gujarat – March 2013 – 73%

S.S.C from Shree Vardhman Vidyalaya- Mehsana, Gujarat - March-2011-84%

# SKILLS

#### **Software**

Microsoft Office 365, MS Visio, Balsamiq, MS SharePoint, Smartsheet, JIRA, Figma

#### **Technical Skills**

SQL, UNIX

### **Business Analyst Skills**

- Excellent documentation skills, communication, and organizational skills.
- Preparing Business Requirement Document (BRD), Software Requirement Specification (SRS), Functional Requirement Specification (FRS), User Manuals, Process Documents and User Stories.
- ✓ Preparing Wireframes using Balsamiq.
- ✓ Preparing Prototypes using Figma and Adobe XD.
- ✓ Managing project management lifecycle & Requirement Gathering using Aha!
- ✓ Knowledge SDLC Models such as Agile Methodologies and Waterfall Model.
- ✓ Preparing UML Diagrams Use Case, Class Diagram, Activity Diagram, Sequence Diagram and System Flowcharts.
- ✓ Experience in GAP analysis and preparing Effort Estimation Sheets.
- ✓ Doing Requirement Planning and Risk Identification for the products.

#### EXPERIENCE

# Business Analyst | Panamax Infotech Ltd. | Ahmedabad

**September 2021– Present** 

- ✓ Panamax Inc., the technology arm of Bankai Group, is a global leader in developing FinTech and telecommunication technologies for telecom operators, carriers, MNOs and MVNOs. Panamax's Business Support System (BSS) products extend converged & interconnect roaming solutions, rating, retail subscriber prepaid and postpaid billing, deal management, fraud management and business process automation solutions. It provides complete suite of CDR Billing, Mediation, Roaming, Reconciliation and Settlement. Panamax's Routing Management is one of the most integral modules of Interconnect solution that provides intelligent routing mechanism helping operators/carriers to gain maximum profit and good quality route to terminate traffic for various destinations.
- ✓ Working in Product Management Team as a Business Analyst.
- ✓ Working in CRM, Billing, Interconnect and Roaming products.

- ✓ Building documents and generating idea for Revenue Assurance (RA) and Fraud Management System (FMS).
- ✓ Providing support for Pre and Post Sales activities.
- ✓ Generating and updating FRS, BRD, User Manuals as and when required.
- Preparing Release Notes and Announcement for the new Product or Sprint Release.
- Preparing Wireframes and Prototypes for the Products.
- Preparing Flowcharts and UML diagrams.
- Collaborating with software developers, product managers, information architects, quality assurance engineers, and technical support engineers to develop product.
- Arranging KT Sessions for developers, quality assurance engineers and other important stakeholders.
- ✓ Managing Product Roadmap with its version releases.
- Arranging Product demo for internal Sales, Presales, Finance, and other stakeholders.
- ✓ Performing UAT and Sanity testing.
- ✓ Preparing Effort Estimation sheets.
- ✓ Managing sprints in ZOHO.

# Associate System Analyst | Nextgen Clearing Pvt. Ltd. | Ahmedabad System Analyst | Nextgen Clearing Pvt. Ltd. | Ahmedabad Senior System Analyst | Nextgen Clearing Pvt. Ltd. | Ahmedabad

August 2017 – March 2018 April 2018 – March 2021 April 2021 – September 2021

- Nextgen offer Award-winning Data and Financial Clearing services along with unique value-added features on a single flexible online platform. Nextgen's solution provides the full spectrum of core data clearing services along with unique value-added features on a single modern and flexible online platform. Intuitive to use and rich in content, DCH platform delivers greater transparency across all aspects of the data clearing process.
- Ensure implementation of Minimal Viable Product (MVP) with all the stakeholders for all demands with large and complex requirements.
- ✓ Assessed, defined, documented scope of projects and responsible for configuring overall system requirements.
- ✓ Performed system analysis, documentation, testing, implementation, and user support for platform transitions.
- Organized system operating procedures, strengthening controls, system maintenance and enhanced overall system performance.
- Supported developers by creating system models, specifications, and requirements.
- ✓ Developed flowcharts and diagrams to describe and lay out logical operational steps.
- ✓ Actively Participated in internal and external Project presentations.
- ✓ Supported development team in preparing the functional specification document for the system.
- Collaborated with Project Managers, Product Managers, Implementation Managers and Customer Support Managers regarding parameters of client projects.
- ✓ Track and proactively follow up on various deadlines assigned to the various team members.
- Actively monitoring and driving team performance, including throughput and quality as per defined company's metrics.
- Ensure team delivers feasibility studies & closes functional specs with Business sign offs in agreed TAT's.
- ✓ Mapping the business requirements with systems and ensuring detailed feasibility of business automation needs with cross partner teams and SME.
- ✓ Supported in QA and UAT testing.
- ✓ RAP/TAP/Mediation file handling.
- ✓ Rerating and recycling of CDRs.
- ✓ Hands on experience in TAP editor and TADIG standards.

## As a Part of Operation Team

- ✓ Working individually or with a team in recommending action, scheduling, and planning projects, and managing projects to completion. Also, providing analysis support and recommended appropriate actions to stakeholders.
- Prepares customers for implementation by planning and/or coordinating training, writing documentation, and providing support.
- ✓ Analyzing data, identifying, and fixing issues by executing appropriate actions.
- ✓ Working closely with cross-functional teams for improving internal processes.

- Designing and using strategy models for identifying and fixing different types of issues.
- ✓ Analyzing the monthly, quarterly, and annual KPIs are met against the contractual commitments for several business units.
- Responsible for assigning daily tasks/work to junior level staff on project teams. Also, updating daily Tasks and Procedures.
- ✓ Monitor the ticket queue for incoming tickets. Update and ensure OTRS tickets are complete and accurate.
- ✓ Timing doing quality checks on the system configurations.
- ✓ Identifying, analyzing, and initiating the escalation process in an organization based on the escalation criteria specified by the organization.
- ✓ Identify possible issues affecting customers and bring them to the attention of the proper point of contact.
- ✓ Working within the designated SLAs.

#### Project Trainee | Infosense Global Pvt. Ltd. | Gandhinagar

Jan 2017 - May 2017

- Developed an application using Oracle ADF, where the Developers are appointed for upcoming or current projects of the company by their team leaders or project managers based on their skills, availability, rating, and experience.
- Coordinated with other developers and support team in developing project plans for prioritized initiatives.

#### **CERTIFICATES**

- ✓ Scrum Fundamental Certificate issued by Scrum Study on 19th June 2021.
- ✓ Six Sigma Yellow Belt (ICYB) issued by Scrum Study on 29th March 2022.